Inventory of Suellen Zima papers, 1988-2013
Hoover Institution Archives
Suellen Zima papers
1988-2013
2015C8
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (4.75 linear feet)
Letters received from Chinese acquaintances, and photographs, relating to social conditions in China.
Zima, Suellen.
Access
The collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical note
Suellen Zima is a traveler, teacher, and a writer. She has spent her life traveling to Bali, China, Korea, Macau, and Taiwan while briefly settling in Israel. Among her numerous articles, Zima is also the author of, “Memories of a Middle-aged Hummingbird,” which in 2008 earned her the First Place in the non-fiction genre by the National League of American Pen Women.
Scope and Contents
Materials in the collection document the life and travels of Suellen Zima, through: correspondence recevied from Chinese acquaintances, photographs, and a signed copy of, "Memories of a Middle-aged Hummingbird."
Americans--China.; China Social conditions.
- Correspondence, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1991 (Box-folder 2: 3-4)
- Correspondence, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box-folder 5: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 4-5)
- Correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1997 (Box-folder 6: 4)
- Correspondence, 1998 (Box-folder 6: 5)
- Correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Correspondence, 2000 (Box-folder 7: 2)
- Correspondence, 2001-2013 (Box-folder 7: 3-4)
- Correspondence with Sherry and Gil Wiseman, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 7: 5)
- Correspondence with Philip, 1992-2007 (Box-folder 7: 6)
- Photo Albums and Photographs, 1988-2010
  Scope and Content
  Photographs of Zima’s travels to China where she was a teacher at a tourism school.
  - Photo Album, 1988 (Text 8)
  - Photo Album, 1988-1992 (Text 8)
  - Photo Album, 1989 (Text 8)
  - Photo Album, 1989 (Text 8)
  - Photo Album, 1989 (Text 8)
  - Photo Album, 1991 (Text 8)
  - Oversize Photos, 1989 (Text 8)
  - Photo Album, 1988-1997 (Text 9)
  - Photo Album, 1995-2010 (Text 9)
- Binder of writings, 1990s (Text 9)
- "Memories of a Middle-aged Hummingbird,", 2006 (Text 9)